Washington and Lee University and Regional Virginia History Research Collection WLU.Coll.0668
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
- Washington and Lee University (Box 19, Box 19-21, Folder 31)
  - Fraternities (Box 20)
    Fraternal organizations; Washington and Lee University
    - Eta Alpha of Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 20, Folder 23)
      Fraternal organizations; Washington and Lee University; Washington and Lee Univerity. Delta Kappa Epsilon
    - General (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Kappa Alpha Order (Box 20, Folder 25)
      Kappa Alpha Order; Washington and Lee University
    - Renaissance (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Sigma Nu (Box 20, Folder 27)
      Washington and Lee University. Sigma Nu Fraternity
  - Freshman Camp, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    Orientation; Washington and Lee University
  - GHQ (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Gymnasium (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Habitat for Humanity (Box 20, Folder 31)
    Habitat for Humanity, inc.; Washington and Lee University
  - Hazing, New York Times Company (Box 20, Folder 32)
    Hazing
  - History (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Honorary Degrees (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Honor System, Young, Neely (Box 20, Folder 35)
    Honor system (Higher education); Washington and Lee University
  - invitations (Box 20, Folder 36)
    Invitation cards; Washington and Lee University; Elrod, John W.; Elrod, Mimi Milner
  - Journalism (Box 20, Folder 37)
    Journalism; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Department; Washington and Lee University
  - Laws and Regulations (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Law School (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Washington and Lee University. School of Law
  - Lee Chapel (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Lee Chapel (Washington and Lee University)
  - Lee Chapel Restoration (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Restoration; Lee Chapel (Washington and Lee University)
  - Lee House (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Washington and Lee University. Lee House. President's House; Washington and Lee University
  - Lenfest Performing Arts Center (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Washington and Lee University. Lenfest Center for the Arts; Washington and Lee University
  - Liberty Hall Academy (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Liberty Hall Academy
  - Masons (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Gateway, 1920; 1 Files (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Washington and Lee University. Memorial Gateway; Washington and Lee University. World War; Washington and Lee University. Alumni
  - The Mink (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Mock Convention (Box 21, Folder 11)
    The Record, Mock Democratic Convention, March 6 and 7, 1992. The cover of this booklet has a sketch of Main Street, looking south, with parade.
    Washington and Lee University. Mock Convention; Washington and Lee University
  - Native American Alumni, 1877-1909 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Biographies of native American Indians, Robert Latham Owen WLU 1877 and Walter Jonathan Turnbull WLU 1909.
    Owen, Robert Latham; Turnbull, Walter Jonathan
  - Plates (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Presidents (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Print Shop Crew (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Push Ball (Box 21, Folder 16)
    Push ball; Washington and Lee University
  - Rectors (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Rings (Box 21, Folder 18)
    Rings; Washington and Lee University
  - Seal (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Songs (Box 21, Folder 20)
    Songs; Washington and Lee University
  - Speaking Tradition at Washington and Lee University, 2002-12-09; Warren, Mame (Mary Elizabeth); 1 Item (Box 21, Folder 20a)
    Washington and Lee University. Speaking Tradition
  - Square and Compass (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Substance Abuse (Box 21, Folder 22)
    Substance abuse; Washington and Lee University
  - Trees (Box 21, Folder 23)
    Colonnade Oaks flyer, Dashiell Dericks '18.
    Trees; Washington and Lee University
  - Troubadour Theatre (Box 21, Folder 24)
    Correspondence between Pres. Robert E. R. Huntley and J. Michale Gallagher, Class of 1979, concerning the death of Drama Prof. Lee Kahn, his work at the Troub, and his dream of a new fine arts complex for Washington and Lee, August 10 and 24, 1981.
    Troubadours; Theater; Kahn, Lee; Washington and Lee University
  - Trustees (Box 21, Folder 25)
    College trustees; Washington and Lee University
  - Tucker Hall (Box 21, Folder 26)
    Washington and Lee University; Washington and Lee University. Tucker Hall
  - Washington and Lee University (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Washington Hall (Box 21, Folder 28)
    Washington and Lee University; Washington and Lee University. Washington Hall
  - Washington Hall Bell (Box 21, Folder 29)
    Bells; Washington and Lee University. Washington Hall; Washington and Lee University
  - World War II (Box 21, Folder 30)
    World War (1939-1945); Washington and Lee University
  - 250th (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Alumni Casualities in the Korean, Persian Gulf, 9/11, Afghanistan, Vietnam, World War I and II wars., 2018-2022-07; Rutherford, John, Class of 1966; 1 Files (Box 21, Folder 31a)
    Lists of Washington and Lee University students or alumni killed during 20th and 21st century wars including the First and Second World Wars, Korea, Vietnam, Persian Gulf and since the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001.
    World War II list updated by John Rutherford in July 1922.
    Persian Gulf War; 9/11; Afghanistan; Vietnam War; World War II
- Washington College (Box 21, Folder 32-33)
  Washington College
  - Enrollments (Box 21, Folder 32)
    School enrollment; Washington and Lee University
  - General, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    President Lee's College: Robert E. Lee and the Renewal, Reformation, and Expansion of Washington College.
    Washington College (Lexington, Va.)
- Wills: Kern, Thomas D., 1919 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  Wills; Kern, Thomas D.
- World War II: Bedford Movement (Box 21, Folder 35)
  World War (1939-1945)
- Zoos (Box 21, Folder 36-37)
  Zoos
  - Mill Mountain (Box 21, Folder 36)
    Zoos; Mill Mountain Zoo
  - Natural Bridge (Box 21, Folder 37)
    Zoos; Virginia -- Natural Bridge; Natural Bridge Zoo
- Addiitional W&L Misc Files
  - Obituary, Fred Hadsel died April 11, 2010, 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Hadsel, Fred L.
  - Obituary, H. Marshall Jarrett died February 9, 2010. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Jarrett, H. Marshall
  - The Story of Lykes. A Publication of Lykes Bros. Steamship Co., Inc., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 3)
    John Wall Lykes, WLU 1908, Joseph Taliaferro Lykes, WLU 1909, Joseph Taliaferro Lykes, Jr. WLU 1941
    Lykes, Joseph; Lykes, John
  - Obituary, Odell McGuire died December 8, 2008., 2 Item (Box 22, Folder 4)
    McGuire, Odell S.
  - Obituary, James C. Rogers dies at Hyattsville., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Rogers, James C.
  - Ranson survived the Civil War, became Staunton lawyer, leader., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Thomas D. Ranson WLU 1859-60
    Ranson, Thomas D.
  - Georgetown's Itinerant Preacher: The Reverend Jacob Ross. Paper presented at the 46th Annual DC History Conference, By L. Paige Whitley., 2019-11-22; Whitley, Paige; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Ross, Jacob
  - Dr. Bean Reads Historical Paper on Rev. John Skinner. Rockbridge County News. November 15, 22, 29, 1945, 3 Item (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Skinner, John
  - Obituary, American Artist, Cy Twombly, Who Scribbled a Unique Path, by Randy Kennedy. The New-York Times., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Boats Beyond the Blue Ridge. The North River Canal Connected Lexington with Richmond and Benefited the Economy of Rockbridge County, but It Did Not Prove Profitable to the the Investors Who Financed It. By Elizabeth Dabney Coleman and W. Edwin Hemphill. Virginia Cavalcade. Spring 1954, 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 10)
    North River Navigation Company
  - Boogher Family, embracing the Lineage of 13 Boogher children, Descendants of Nicholas Boogher, and Rebecca Davis Coombs (Boogher). Compiled and written by Avery H. Reed., Reed, Avery H.; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Boogher Family
  - Jamestowne Society, Application for Membership of John Williams Knapp, Descendant of Thomas Gouldman., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Gouldman Family
  - Barclay family genealogy., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Genealogy compiled by Alex Taylor, whose great grandfather was Alexander Tedford Barclay.
    Barclay family
  - Gilvin family genealogy., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Material given by Tangy (Gilven) Hunter-Hughes, a descendant of Jack Gilvin.
    Gilvin, Jack; African Americans. Rockbridge County, Virginia
  - Garland family genealogy., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Geneaology of Garland family, who bought some of the Washington College slaves.
    Garland family
  - Harman family genealogy., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Genealogy on the Harman family given by Carolyn Scott, which has photos and biographies of Charles Price Harman, born 1868, and his wife, Rachel Primrose "Rose" Cameron Sherrard, and their children.
    Harman family; Sherrard Family
  - Hayslett family genealogy. A partial history of one of the Hayslett families of Rockbridge County, Virginia., 2007; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Hayslett family
  - Lewis family genealogy., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 18)
    Genealogy and biography of Rev. Peter Simon Lewis, the pastor of First Baptist Church, Lexington, Va., 1901-1906.
    African-Americans. Lexington, Virginia; Lewis, Peter Simon; First Baptist Church (Lexington, Va.)
  - William Ramsey, 1727-1789, Early Resident of Pre-Revolutionary Virginia and His Descendants, 2017; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 19)
    Compiled by Tom Vansant Jr., Descendant of Dr. James Ramsey, Son of William.
    Ramsey family
  - Anna Clarke Rogers. Mrs. James Webb Rogers, the former Anna Phillips Clarke., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Descendant of Robert Alexander of Virginia, founder of the first classical school west of the Blue Ridge Mountains, which became the present Washington and Lee University.
    Rogers family
  - The California Society of the Sons of the American Revolution. Application for membership of Robert Swartout Stearns, descendant of Major John Hays., 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 21)
    Stearns family
  - The Way We Were by Ann McClung. Beginning three centuries ago, Scotch-Irish settlers built log cabins throughout Rockbridge County. More than 400 of these earliest of American homes still stand--some abandoned, others partially renovated or restored., 2009-11-19; McClung, Ann; 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 22)
    Log Cabins
  - Some Ferries Along the James River above Lynchburg, Virginia, by Doug MacLeod, MacLeod, Douglas; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 23)
    Ferries--Virginia
  - Big Spring Mill, Works Progress Administration Survey, 1930s and For Sale or Rent Advertisement, Staunton Spectator, September 25, 1860., 2 Item (Box 22, Folder 24)
    Big Spring Mill
  - The Weekly Independent, Circulates in Alleghany, Bath, Botetourt, Craig and Rockbridge Counties. Clifton Forge, Virginia (Photocopy), 1885-11-06; 2 Item (Box 22, Folder 25)
    Clifton Forge, Virginia
  - Discover History & Heritage. Born on the Rails: The Roanoke and New River valleys boomed during the golden age of the railroad., 2015-08; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 26)
    Shenandoah Valley Railroad
  - Midland Trail, U. S. 60, is the "Main Street" of America, newspaper articles, 1927-1929, 1931, photocopies. (Box 22, Folder 27)
    Virginia. Department of Highways
  - Fairfield High School, Commencement Exercise undated invitation and program, 1927; 2 Item (Box 22, Folder 28)
    Fairfield, Virginia
  - Theater at Lime kiln presents On Borrowed Time, program, 1999; 1 Item (Box 22, Folder 29)
    Lime Kiln Theater, Rockbridge County, Virginia
  - William Drummond home, 1878 to 1896, North Main Street, Lexington, Virginia, which was also owned by the Beeton family and was the Beeton Laundry. Also photocopies of photos of the Beeton home on North Randolph Street, Lexington, Virginia., 1 Files (Box 22, Folder 30)
    Drummond family; Beeton family
  - Obituary, Prof. Severn Duvall, Dies at 87. Reminiscenses by W&L Professors Jim Warren and George Ray., 2012-03-02; 3 Item (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Duvall, Severn Parker Costin
  - Obituary, Prof. of Art Emeritus I-Hsiung Ju Dies., 2012-03-17; 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Friends of W&L Library Honors Betty Kondayan. Receives John Rogers Award, along with Roger Mudd, a 1950 graduate of Washington and Lee., 2012-05-12; 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Kondayan, Betty Ruth; Mudd, Roger
  - Gardening in Rockbridge County, A Monthly Guide, compiled by The Rockbridge Area Master Gardeners Association., 2000-08; 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Rockbridge Area Master Gardeners Association
  - First to Fight: The American Flyers of the Lafayette Escadrille in World War One, by Chalres Flood., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 5)
    France. Armele. Escadrille Lafayette
  - Australia on the Brain: Mary Custis Lee in Hobart Town, January-March 1877, Tasmanian Historical Research Association, December 2010, by Susan Carter Vogel., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Lee, Mary Custis
  - History of the First Baptist Church, Buena Vista, Virginia., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 7)
    First Baptist Church (Buena Vista, Virginia)
  - Long-Time Service by Brown Colbert Borgus Remembered During Ceremony at VMI., 1999-02-04; 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Borgus served VMI as head waiter during the period between September 1919 and September 1955. He then returned for a brief period between the months of September and December 1958.
    Borgus, Brown Colbert; African-Americans. Lexington, Virginia
  - No Stranger to Difficulty: The Friends and Relations of Patrick Henry, by Neal O. Hammon., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Henry, Patrick
  - Descendants of Adam Dickinson., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Dickinson family
  - Mason family genealogy and family group sheets., 2 Item (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Mason family
  - Griffin family genealogy., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 12)
    William Griffin born 1792 in Lexington, married November 21, 1816 in Virginia, and died 1850 in Boone County, Indiana.
    Griffin family
  - Grigsby family genealogy., 22 Item (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Includes "Genealogy of the Grigsby Family," In Part, Including a Brief Sketch of the Porter Family, Republished by Robert Hall McCormick, Chicago, 1905. Originally published by William H. Grigsby, December 1878.
    Grigsby family; Porter Family
  - Holder's of Tavern's Licenses 1778-1864., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Taverns (Inns)--Rockbridge County, Virginia
  - Self-Guided Tour of Washington and Lee, 2006-03 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Information on Marriage registers of Freedmen, by Elaine C. Everly, The U.S. National Archives & Records Administration, Fall 1973. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    African Americans. Freedman
  - Celebrating 100 Years of Collegiate Registrars, by Scott Dittman, W&L University Registrar., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Washington and Lee first established a registrar's office in 1910.
    Washington and Lee University. Registrar
  - Two In Family Fatally Injured by Lightning, Fairfield, Virginia., 1969; 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 18)
    McGuffin Family
  - Hartless family, 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 19)
    African Americans. Amherst County, Virginia; Hartless family
  - Obituary, Joseph Goldsten died October 11, 2012. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    Goldsten, Joseph
  - Obituary, Charles F. "Chuck" Phillips, Jr. died October 17, 2012., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 21)
    Phillips, Charles Franklin, Jr.
  - The Jurisprudence of Slavery, Freedom, and Union at Washington College, 1831-1861, by Alfred L. Brophy., 2 Item (Box 23, Folder 22)
    Also includes: Multivariate Analysis Through Narrative History, by Alfred L. Brophy. Reviewing G. Edward White, Law in American History: From the Colonial Years Through the Civil War.
    African Americans. Washington College; White, G. Edward; Law. United States
  - Kerrs Creek Ruritan Club, 50th Anniversary; 2 Item (Box 23, Folder 23)
    Includes 50th Anniversary Program and a 50th Anniversary Booklet with history, which includes members. The Location of Organizational Meeting, December 1939, held at the Mayflower in Lexington, Virginia.
    Kerrs Creek Ruritan Club
  - Catherine Von Bora Alphin Hotinger,1901-1980, biography and miscelleaneous papers., 1916-1927; 33 Item (Box 23, Folder 24)
    Includes school reports, marriage certificate, wedding invitation, and letter from Harvey before marriage. Also included are photographs of Catherine Alphin, her parents and siblings.
    Related Materials
    See Catherine's 1922 Elizabethan College yearbook (Rare LD 7251 .S32 E44 v.5 1922). She played basketball and her cousin Hope Welsh also attended there. The school burned while the students were at home on Christmas vacation.
    A Lutheran Sunday School pin, which may have belonged to Catherine or one of her Alphin family members, while members at Bethany Lutheran Church in Rockbridge County, Virginia.
    Alphin Family; Hotinger, Catherine Von Bora Alphin; Hotinger, Harvey Lewis; Virginia. State Teachers College at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.); Virginia. State Normal School for Women. Harrisonburg, Virginia; Highland Belle School; Alphin, Leonidas LyCurgus; Alphin, Olive Virginia Teaford; Virginia. Eliizabethan College. Salem, Virginia; Welsh, Hope
  - Supplemental Gasoline Ration and Mileage Ration, American & Reliance Scales receipt, and Commonwealth of Virginia, Virginia Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Sales Permit No.2, Civilian Registrant, Coupon book, which belonged to Harvey Lewis Hotinger, and memorandum book with farming expenses, 1930-1944; 8 Item (Box 23, Folder 25)
    Also includes a Myers Hardware Company memorandum book, which has some of Harvey's farm expenses for 1943.
    Inludes a pencil marked Southern States Cooperative.
    World War II; World War II. Alcohol; World War II. Gasoline; Hotinger, Harvey Lewis; Myers Hardware Co., Inc., Lexington, Virginia; Farming. Rockbridge County, Virginia.
  - Albert Orr McCown farm, Kerrs Creek, 8 miles west of Lexington. Insurance of buildings by son and daughter-in-law, Albert T. and Josephine H. McCown,1983-1984 and Excavation and Grading Contract between the heirs of Albert O. and Buddy Sibold, December 23, 1985., 2 Item (Box 23, Folder 26)
    McCown, Albert Orr
  - Sketch of Mary Rader farm near Buffalo Creek, by W. E. Tilson and Realtors., 1 Item (Box 23, Folder 27)
    Rader, Mary E.
  - Margaret Virginia Tardy (Mrs. Albert Orr McCown) miscellaneous papers, 1913-1949; 8 Item (Box 23, Folder 28)
    Includes biography, a couple of letters, one of which is from her sister, Elizabeth, a letter that School Board has raised her salary, a post card from brother Thomas, wedding invitation announcing marriage to Albert Orr McCown, and an W&L Bicentennial Celebration invitation to her and Albert. Also included is insurance receipt, no date.
    McCown, Margaret Virginia Tardy
  - Voters, Rockbridge County, Applications and Registrations., 1942-11-02-1965; 1 Files (Box 23, Folder 29)
    One item is a Guide Ballot for the General Election, November 2, 1942 for Senator from the 20th Senatorial District of Virginia. (Rockbridge County)
    Voting. Rockbridge County, Virginia
  - Rockbridge National Bank, Lexington, Virginia. miscellaneous, Hank, J. D., Jr.; 4 Item (Box 23, Folder 30)
    Virginia Laws Made Plain: Laws and Legal Forms Prepared for the Use of Business Men, Farmers, and Mechanics, compiled by Hon. J. D. Hank, Jr.. Presented by Rockbridge National Bank, Lexington, Virginia, 1923.
    Rockbridge National Bank, Lexington, Virginia, pocket calendar, 1930.
    Rockbridge National Bank, Lexington, Virginia, check, Sept. 21, 1935, made to Fred Berry from Mrs. Harvey L. Hotinger.
    The Rockbridge National Bank pencil showing the 1960 Football Schedule for the Lexington Scarlet Hurricanes.
    Rockbridge National Bank (Lexington, Va.); Laws. Virginia
  - F. W. Kling, Jr. material, 1968-11-20-1976-10-12; Kling, F. W., Jr.; 3 Item (Box 23, Folder 31)
    Photocopy of Kling's letter of resignation as Supt. of the Buena Vista School Board.
    Invitation and program for the official dedication of the F. W. Kling, Jr. Elementary School, Buena Vista, Virginia, October 12, 1976.
    Buena Vista School Board; F. W. Kling, Jr. Elementary School. Buena Vista, Virginia
  - PURINA CHOWS pencil, Farmer's Supply Co., Lexington, VA and Purina Mills, St. Louis, Missouri advertisement for Ralston-Purina Cereals., 2 Item (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Rockbridge Laundry and Dry Cleaners, Inc. Envelope (Box 23, Folder 33)
    Rockbridge Laundry and Dry Cleaners, Inc.
  - Rockbridge Farmer's Coop pocket ledger and money pouch., 2 Item (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Highland Maple Syrup and Festival brochure, 1975-03; 2 Item (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Included is a Highland Maple Syrup advertisement, no date.
    Maple Festival (Highalnd County, Virginia)
  - Glen Maury Park, Buena Vista, Virginia brochure, 1 Item (Box 24, Folder 3)
    Glen Maury Park (Buena Vista, Virginia)
  - Lake Robertson, Rockbridge County, Virginia brochure, 1 Item (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Rockbridge Vineyard and Winery Company history, Rockbridge County, Virginia, 1989; Rouse, Parke Shepherd, III; 1 Item (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Shep Rouse, W&L Graduate 1976
    Rockbridge Vineyard and Winery Company (Rockbridge County, Virginia)
  - Franklin Gardner Walter, Civil War Diary and Letters, with sketch of his life, 1863-1865; Carter, Erle Preston; Walter, Frederick William; Walter, Dorsey; 1 Item (Box 24, Folder 6)
    The War Time Diary, F. G. Walter (1837-1930), Co. A, 39th Battalion, Virginia Cavalry, Confederate States Army, June 20, 1863 - April 19, 1865.
    Correspondence from Frank, to his brother and mother, December 10, 1862 - June 23, 1864. One letter from Frank's brother, Dorsey, to him, December 31, 1862.
    Walter, Franklin Gardner; Confederate States of America. Army. Virginia Cavalry Battalion 39th, Co.A
  - University Cleaners calendar, 1978; 1 Item (Box 24, Folder 7)
    The University Cleaners businesses were located at 7 N. Jefferson Street, Lexington, VA and 2028 Magnolia Street, Buena Vista, VA.
    University Cleaners. (Lexington and Buena Vista, Virginia)